Guide to the World War I Posters File [1914]-1920 PR 55-7
New-York Historical Society
- Series V: Relief Appeals, 5
  - Subseries V.3: Children's Relief, 26
    - Children's / Year / Send aid / to the Mayor's Committee of Women on National Defense, 1919 - 1918 (Folder 35)
      Big smiling baby; NY waterfront rear
    - Know the History / of / Your Country, 1919 (Folder 35)
      3 "rings:" 1. Past conditions / history, 2. Present problems / cures, 3. Future reforms / ideals
    - A Knowledge of English / is the Gateway / to / American Life / American Citizenship / American Ideals, 1919 (Folder 35)
      family of immigrants opening door marked "English Language" to scene of America
    - The good citizen / Works for public health, 1919 (Folder 35)
      children quaranteened at home; "measles here" sign on door
    - The good citizen / Is careful with matches, 1919 (Folder 35)
      firemen at burning building
    - Be a Good Neighbor / Cover the Garbage / Tie Up Papers, 1919 (Folder 35)
      man entering a bakery; papers strewn on sidewalk; flies on uncovered bin of garbage
  - Subseries V.4: Animals' Relief / American Red Star Animal Relief, 27
    - "Help the Horse / Save the soldier" / Please join / The American Red Star Animal Relief / National Headquarters, Albany, NY (Folder 36)
      Soldier hugging wouldned hosrse before bombed out house; picture labeled "Good-bye, Old Man"
    - American / Red Star / Animal Relief (Folder 36)
      Red star
    - Help him to help us! / Help the / horse to / save the / soldier /The American Red Star Animal Relief / National Headquarters, Albany, NY (Folder 36)
      Uncle Sam leading a horse; red star
  - Subseries V.5: United War Work Campaign, 28
    - For / your /boy / United War Work Campaign / November 11 18, 1918 (Folder 37)
      2 soldiers resting over coffee; YMCA sign rear
    - If you only knew! / How much joy your / dollars bring "over there" / You'd give and give / and give!!! / United War Work Campaign, Nov 11to 18, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Soldeir with hot coffee, sandwich / logos of different participating organizations
    - A Club Dinner / The Spirit of / War Camp / Community Service / United War Work Campaign (Folder 37)
      Sailors at dining tables; Chinese scrolls on walk-rear
    - Songs of today / And yesterday / The Spirit of / War Camp / Community Service / United War Work Campaign (Folder 37)
      Sailors around elderly lady playing the piano
    - Every girl pulling / For victory / Victory Girls / United War Work Campaign (Folder 37)
      Woman rowing a boat
    - Back our Girls over there / Y.W.C.A. / United War Work Campaign (Folder 37)
      Wman in unifrom at switcboard; troops in rear
    - See him through / Help us to / help the boys / National Catholic War Council / Knights of Columbus / United War Work Campaign Week of November 11, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Man in K of C uniform; soldiers in battle
    - Workers / Lend your strength / to the red triangle / heltp the "Y" help the / fighters fight / United War Wrk Campaign November 11 18, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Laborer carrying slap labeled YMCA; fighting soldier rear
    - When the boys come home / While I was over there / what were you doing here? / Students of America / How will you answer him? / United War Work Campaign Nov 11 1 8, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Soldier facing student wearing mortarboard
    - Jewish Welfare Board / United War Work Campaign / Week of November 11, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Soldier carrying Torah, hebrew books; box on his shoulders with music and violin
    - I gotta make that train! / Nix on the / A.W.O.L. / Oh, you hospitable New Yorkers don't let / your uniformed guests overstay their passes / New york War Camp Community Service, 5 East 40th Street, Murray Hill 8210. (Folder 37)
      Soldier running to make his train
    - A million boys behind / a million fighters / Every American boy / should enroll in the / Victory Boys / United War Work Campaign November 11 18 (Folder 37)
      Soldier with bayonet; boy behind him with arm on his shoulder
    - Civilians / when we go / through this / we need all the / help and comfort / you can give / the Jewish Welfare Board / United War Work Campaign, Week of Nvember 11, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Soldier in battle; Jewish star
    - (Tribute to YMCA) I wish unreservedly to commend its work for the army / Pershing / United War Work Campaign, Nov 11 18, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Portrait of Pershing; YMCA's red triangle
    - The Jewish Welfare Board / United War Work Campaign, Week of November 11, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Soldiers welcoming Jewish family into Jewish Welfare building
    - Home hospitality / the Spirit of the / war camp / community service / United War Work Campaign (Folder 37)
      Soldiers at meal with a civilian family
    - Invitations to homes / and entertainments / the spirit of / war camp community service / United War Wrok Campaign (Folder 37)
      Soldiers and sailors surrounding a lady at a table writing notes
    - Oh, Boy! / That's the girl! / The Salvation Army Lassie Keep her on the job / United War Work Campaign Nov 11 18, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Salvation army woman distributing doughnuts to soldier
    - New York will give / "One / Day's / Pay" / To the United War Work Campaign / "Leave it to Little Old New York!" / New York's share is $35,000,000. / United War Work Campaign, 1918 (Folder 37)
    - "Hey Fellows!" / Your money / brings the / book we / neeed when / we want it. / American Library Association / United War Work Campaign Week of November 11 18, 1918 (Folder 37)
      Sailor reading; soldier distribuiting books
    - 7 in 1 / Our / boys / health / then / home (Folder 38)
    - This Synogague / is behind / the United / War Work / Campaign / for the boys / over there (Folder 38)
    - United / we / serve / YMCA / National Catholic War Council / K. of C. / Jewish Welfare Board / War Camp Community Service / American Library Service / Salvation Army (Folder 38)
      Number 170 at corners of 'plaque' with above listing
    - 7 in 1 / United War Work Campaign (Folder 38)
    - United War Work Campaign / Honor Roll (Folder 38)
      Honor Roll of 100 numbered lines / War Work logo above
    - 7 (Folder 38)
      Huge 7
    - Our war workers bring the only / touch of home comforts to the / boys over there GIVE! / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - 7 in 1 / Give! / One year / to get our / boys home / keep them well (Folder 38)
    - Doesn't your heart tell you to make a / little sacrifice toward helping over / there? Obey the impulse now! / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - 7 in 1 / Give! / To keep / our /boys / clean / and /healthy / then / home (Folder 38)
    - Take your place in the great / crusade! Give until you experi / ence the joy of giving!! GIVE NOW! / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - All the money you will take with / you into the next world is what / you give in this one GIVE NOW / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - Can't you see the boys over there amidst / the mud and blood and hell of war, the cold / and fatigue and homesickness? You can furnish some relief / Give all you can! / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - Turn your dollars into saviors! / Buy good influences for the / boys over there! GIVE! / United War Work (printed upside down) (Folder 38)
    - Mere dollars are turned into golden / sunshine in the hearts of the boys / over there by our war workers GIVE / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - Their very souls cry out for a little / taste of home. You can supply it / through our war workers GIVE! / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - 7 Morale (Folder 38)
    - Every cent you give helps bring some / home comforts to our boys overseas / The Bronx quota is $650,000 / Lets double it! / Give in the Bronx / Give where you live / United War Work Campaign (Folder 38)
    - Victory award / Pledged / Amount paid (Folder 38)
      "thermometer" with slogan "watch it go up" (triangular shape)
    - This Church / is behind / the United / War Work / Campaign / for the boys / over there (Folder 38)
    - Your dollars will buy loving kindness kelp / fullness, sympathy, warmth, good cheer for / the boys over there in the trenches GIVE / United War Work (Folder 38)
    - Give! / United War Work Campaign (Folder 38)
    - My patriotic duty / Is / Red Cross work / At the / ___ on ___ / If / I fail / He dies, 1918 (Folder 39)
      2 RC nurses and a wounded soldier
- Series VI: Organizational, 6
  Series VI: Organizational, includes a variety of posters relating to various relief and membership efforts by the Red Cross, the YWCA, the YMCA, and other organizations.
  - Subseries VI.1: Red Cross, 29
    - unspecified (Folder 39)
      Soldier with arm in sling; RC nurse lighting his pipe
    - Join the Red Cross / Wear your button / It is an evidences of your loyalty, 1919 (Folder 39)
      Button with Red Cross and 1919
    - Be one of / The first to aid / Enlist now / U.S.A. Ambulance Corps / 25 / West 80th St, NYC, 1917 (Folder 39)
      Soldiers driving Red Cross truck
    - 10,000,000 members / By Christmas / On Christmas Eve / A candle in every window and / Red Cross members / In every home (Folder 39)
      Lit candle in window with Red Cross
    - Answer the / Christmas roll call / Join the Red Cross (Folder 39)
      Greatest mother in the world image and church scene
    - Join the Red Cross / All you need is a / Heart and a dollar (Folder 39)
      Red Cross nurse reaching out
    - Make good the promise / Second War Fund / One hundred million dollars (Folder 39)
      Pot with coins "keep it full;" map of England, France, Italy with Red Cross truck "over there"
    - The comforter (Folder 40)
      RC nurse comforting woman and child on war torn terrain
    - Third Red Cross roll call (Folder 40)
      RC nurse reaching out
    - You can help / American Red Cross (Folder 40)
      Woman knitting
    - Hold up your end / War Fund Week / One hundred million dollars (Folder 40)
      RC nurse holding up stretcher
    - "Help" (Folder 40)
      RC nurse holding wounded soldier
    - Help send across / The Red Cross / President Woodrow Wilson / Proclaims / June 18 25 / Red Cross Week / Minnesota / Must raise / $2,000,000 / Saint Paul / Must Over / Subscribe again (Folder 40)
      RC Nurse ministering wounded woldier on war torn territory
    - Learn the meaning / Of "sacrifice" / Give till it hurts / American Red Cross (Folder 40)
      Same as "Greatest Mother in the World"
    - unspecified (Folder 40)
      RC Nurse reaching out directly to viewer, soldiers on parade rear
    - If I fail he dies / Work / For the / Red Cross, 1918 (Folder 40)
      2 RC nurses helping wounded soldier
    - Help / The / Red Cross (Folder 40)
      RC nurse, wounded soldier raising hand for help
    - Make our / American Red Cross / In peace / As in war / "The greatest mother / In the world" / Third Red Cross roll call / November 2 11 1919 (Folder 40)
      RC nurse cradeling wounded soldier
    - The / Greatest mother / In the world (Folder 40)
    - Keep this / Hand of / Mercy at / Its work / War Fund Week / One hundred million dollars (Folder 40)
      Arm with red cross on sleevel harboring war victims
    - Join / The greatest mother (Folder 40)
      RC nurse watching over the globe
    - Red Cross / Christmas roll call / Where / Columbia / Sets / Her name / Let / Every one of you / Follow / Her, 1918 (Folder 40)
      Columbia and RC nurse
    - The roll call / A masque of the Red Cross / by Percy Mackaye (Folder 40)
      Theatrical figure (in toga) pointing to Red Cross
    - Five thousand / By June / Graduate nurses / Your country needs you (Folder 40)
      RC nurse, barracks rear
    - The spirit of America / Join, 1919 (Folder 40)
      RC nurse as Lady Liberty, carrying US flag
    - Second / Red Cross / War Fund (Folder 41)
      Soldier carrying dead soldier on his shoulders
    - "Inasmuch as ye have done it / Unto one of the least of these" / Help your Red Cross (Folder 41)
      Image of Christ and church; nurse ministering to wounded on battlefield
    - Put fighting blood in your business Here's his record/ Does he get a job?" / Arthur Woods, Assistant to the Secretary of War (Folder 41)
      soldiers on French battlefield
    - I summon you to / The comradeship / Woodrow Wilson, 1918 (Folder 41)
    - [In Japanese] (Folder 41)
      Wounded soldiers set in Japanese caligraphy
    - Over here too / Red Cross will help /See your home service section (Folder 41)
      Wounded soldiers, sailors
    - "The first three!" / Give till it hurts they gave till they / Died (Folder 41)
      Memorial wreaths with faces of Hay, Enright, Gresham
    - Loyalty to the one means / Loyalty to both (Folder 41)
      Soldier carrying US flag /Red Cross soldier with RE flag side by side
    - He can win! / The Federal Board provides training / Consult the local / Red Cross home service sectrion (Folder 41)
      soldier at writing desk with clipers, ink, smoking pipe
    - The Challenge / Public health campaign / Join the crusade / Thrid Red Cross Roll Call / November 2 11 (Folder 41)
      Grim Reaper (disease and epidemics on scythe), crusader carrying shiled marked Red Cross
    - Caring for / American soldiers / In England Bulletin No 7 / Issued by War Council of the American Red Cross (Folder 41)
      Soldier, Trafalgar Square rear
    - American Red Cross / Our boys need / SOX / Knit your bit (Folder 42)
      Pile of wool and knitting needles in basket; Red Cross rear
    - Ten Million / New Members / by Christmas (Folder 42)
      Window with Xmas tree inside home and Red Cross Service Flag in window
    - Join Here, 1917 (Folder 42)
      American flags; Red Cross flags crossed
    - "There!" / In peace as in war / Your membership does it Join / Third Red Cross Roll Call / Nov 2 11, 1919 (Folder 42)
      Photograph at the $5,000,000 oil refinery fire, Brooklyn, September 13, 1919
    - 10,000,000 Members / By Christmas / On Christmas Eve / A candle in every / Window and / Red Cross Members / in every home (Folder 42)
      Lit candle, Red Cross before window
    - Answer the / Red Cross / Christmas Roll Call, 1918 (Folder 42)
      Snow covered tree and house with Red Cross Service Flag in window
    - Motherless / Fatherless / Starving / How much / to save these little lives? (Folder 42)
      Red Cross nurse protecting French Children
    - Have you a / Red Cross Service Flag?, 1918 (Folder 42)
      Child pasting Red Cross Service Flag on Window
    - Join / The American / Red Cross / All you need is a / ___ and a ___ (Folder 43)
      Punched out figurines with red paper backing for worrd "join" and images of red cross, heart and a dollar
    - Nurses / Of America!!! / The lives of / Our soldiers / and sailors / Depend on you / Will you enroll? (Folder 43)
      Red cross
    - The Red Cross / Needs you / Join now / Be patriotic be humane, 1917 (Folder 43)
    - Join (Folder 43)
      Red cross on navy ground
    - Join / All you need / Is a heart / And a dollar (Folder 43)
    - Join now / One dollar / Everyone a / Member (Folder 43)
    - To the / Citizens of Connecticut / In the nationwide movement to collect $100,000,000 for the Second War Fund of the American Red Cross there has been allotteed to the people of this State the / Provelidge and responsibility of subscribing $2,000,000 .. (Folder 43)
    - A Vote for / Is a vote for humanity (Folder 43)
    - Honor Roll / The following members of this organization have enrolled as members of the Red Cross for 1919 (Folder 43)
    - The Red Cross needs you / Join now / Subscribing membership / $2 a year (Folder 43)
    - Patriotic rally / July 4th, 1918 / On Long Ridge Church Green / Auspices Long Ridge and West Redding / Red Cross Branch (Folder 43)
    - Have you / A Red Cross / Service / Flag in / Your home? / Classes of membership.. .. .., 1917 (Folder 43)
    - Think what you can / Afford to give / Then double it (Folder 43)
    - Will you be one / of a million workers / to secure members for / the American Red Cross / Third Red Cross Roll Call, Nov 2 11 (Folder 43)
    - We belong / 100% strong / 1919 (Folder 43)
    - We belong / 100% strong / 1920 (Folder 43)
    - If you knew / A day's pay would / Save a life / Would you give? / One day a month? (Folder 43)
    - A little / Starving child / Brought back / To life / Because / You went without / some luxury (Folder 43)
    - Need your / Old clothes / For the / Belgians / Leave them at / Osborn Hall / Sunday morning (Folder 43)
    - Read these facts / About your / American Red Cross / Its purpose / It is working for / Your army your navy your allies and you (Folder 43)
    - Nurses of America / Humanity calls you / What is / Your answer? / Enroll now with / the American Red Cross (Folder 43)
    - Nurses / The call from / Noman's land / is / "Come across" (Folder 43)
    - Nurses / This means you / Our wounded / Need care / They need you (Folder 43)
    - The Red Cross needs you / Join Now / President Wilson says: / ExPresident Taft says: / ExPresident Roosevelt has said.. .. .. (Folder 43)
      Red Cross
    - Red Cross Christmas Roll Call, Dec 16 23rd (Folder 43)
      2 Red Crosses
    - Old fashioned / Husking Bee / Under auspices of the Junior Guard / Benefit of the Red Cross / Friday Dec 27th / Mark Twain Library / Dancing / Admission / 35c (Folder 43)
    - Proclamation / By President Wilson / (reurging a "generous response to the Third Red Cross Roll Call), 1919 (Folder 43)
    - Proclamation / By the President of the United States / To the school children of America / Urging them to join the Junior Red Cross (Folder 43)
    - Give (Folder 43)
      Red Cross on navy ground
    - While someone gives / His life what / Are you giving? / Think a minute (Folder 43)
  - Subseries VI.2: YWCA, 30
    - The girl reserves / of the YWCA / Help us put / The blue triangel / Over the top (Folder 44)
      Girl with YMCA logo on shirt making a shopt at basketball
    - Ain't it a grand and glorious feelin'? / The men know / Home folks know / YWCA / Hostess House / in Seventy Camps (Folder 44)
      Cartoon strip from NY Tribune - soldier homesick and suddenly meeting wife and child in Hostess House at YWCA
    - Board / and / Lodging / for relatives of /Soldiers and Sailors / 30 East 52 Street, NYC / 375 Lexington Ave (Corner of 41st St), NYC / Hostess House Committee / Terms 75c a night (Folder 44)
    - What the W stands for / Welfare and Women / in War Work (Folder 44)
      Blue YWCA tirangle with W circled
    - How the blue triangle / Helps in France (Folder 44)
      YWCA blue triangle with W Circled
    - YWCA (Folder 44)
    - Stand behind the / Country's girlhood / YWCA / New York's Share $1,750,000 / January 7th to 14th (Folder 44)
      Head of girl
    - Remember the girl behind / the man behind the gun /YWCA / War Work Council (Folder 44)
      Gilr reaching out through YWCA triangle
    - YWCA / In service / For the girls / Of the world, 1919 (Folder 44)
      Girl before YMCA plaque
  - Subseries VI.3: YMCA, 31
    - Help us / Help / Our boys / Y M/W CA (Folder 45)
      Woman in YMCA uniform hanging poster with this message
    - Happenings at the sign of the red triangle in hany lands, 1917 (Folder 45)
      12 photos in various activities sponsored by the YMCA
    - unspecified (Folder 45)
      Soldiers filing into YMCA hut
    - YMCA / YWCA / His / Home / Over there (Folder 45)
      Red YMCA triangle; blue YWCA tirangle
    - War Work Week: November 11 19 / YMCA / War Work / With the colors / Local council in each town / New England War Work Council / 324 Little Building, Boston, 1917 (Folder 45)
      YMCA Red triangle logo
    - War Work Week: November 11 19 / Major General John F. O'Ryan says: / "Money can be turned over to the YMCA with every / Confidence.. ..", 1917 (Folder 45)
      Photo of Major General O'Ryan at his desk
    - Marked out by a line / of white tape the / Road from Hell leads / to a little bit of Heaven (Folder 45)
      Wounded soldier being helped past white ribbon with sighn reading "for walking, wounded / YMCA / Free Refreshments"
    - War Work Week: November 11 19 / Gen John Pershing says: / "The work now being done by the YMCA for the comfort and enter / tainment of your soldiers in France is very important", 1917 (Folder 45)
      Gen Pershing
    - Manchester City tramways / YMCA / Hut week collection / Put your gift into the collecting / Box on the car platform (Folder 45)
      Soldiers logging throgh snow toYMCA hut
    - War Work Week: November 11 19 /Maj Gen Hugh L. Scott says: / "I do not know what the army would do / Without the YMCA.", 1917 (Folder 45)
      Maj Gen Hugh L. Scott
    - War Work Week: November 11 19 / Secretary of War Newton D. Baker says of the YMCA (.. ..), 1917 (Folder 45)
      Newton D. Baker
    - unspecified (Folder 45)
      Soldier watching men filing into hut marked YMCA
  - Subseries VI.4: Miscellaneous Organizations, 32
    - "Share and Have" / Benjamin Franklin (Folder 46)
      Ben Franklin and Statue of Liberty
    - The Hand Across / the Sea / Week Oct 13 20, 1918 (Folder 46)
      Arm labeled "war emergency fund" extended from church to our mission field carrying apurse with money and Liberty Bonds spilling out
    - The Meaning of America (Folder 46)
      photos: Statue of Liberty, Armed Freedom, Dome of Capitol
    - "Keep the / Work of / the church / at concert / Pitch" / Woodrow Wilson (Folder 46)
      church and congregants / soldiers on the battlefield
    - Public notice / No 1 / Congress has deided that the / Government of the United States Will issue regular forms of Insur / ance policies to which the present / War risk term policies may be converteed (Folder 46)
    - $196,000 War Emergency Fund / !132,000 Liquidation Fund / Make your Liberty / Bonds work for church / and country Oct 13 20, 1918 (Folder 46)
      Liberty Bond
    - Our War Emergency Fund why? / Higher cost / of travel / of building / of medicines / of rents and fuel / of ministerial relief / of necessary salaries / of postage and printing / must be met by emergency fund that the / Work of the Church Boards [.. ..], 1918 (Folder 46)
    - We need an army to protect us (Folder 46)
      Belgian children, flag bearers (courtsey of Red Cross Magazine); photo of trees cut down by Germans (courtsey Univ of State of NY)
    - Our Church's Duty / in the war / We must raise $500,000 in January for this /work in 1918 / William Lawrence, Bishop of Massachusetts, / Chariman, The Church War Commission (Folder 46)
    - Awake and Safeguard America (Folder 46)
      Soldiers lined up under American Flag (image courtsey of NY Illustrated Post Card and Novelty Co)
    - Public Notice / No 2/ Premium Rates for / All froms of govern / ment insurance (Folder 46)
    - Public Notice / No 3 / All Premium payments for / War risk term policies or / For the new government / insurance policies may be / Made / by / Cash .. Check / PostOffice / MoneyOrder (Folder 46)
- Series VII: Miscellaneous, 7
  Series VII: Miscellaneous, serves as an umbrella category for many foreign posters, news bulletins, foreign causes, and a variety of other war-related topics.
  - Subseries VII.1: Miscellaneous, 33
    - For a war memorial field in Central Park (Folder 47)
      Proposed plan, including victory arch, fountain of peace, historical museum
    - Welcome / The American Legion / Madison Square Garden, October 4, 1919 (Folder 47)
      Soldier, sailor, saluting oval portrait of Legionnare
    - Souscrive 2 / Au IVeme Emprunt / et le drapeau tn= / colore a Strasbourg / Annoncera au / Monde le regne / de la Paix de le / Liberte, de Justice (Folder 47)
      Soldiers approaching Strasbourg Catherdrial flying French flag
    - Pershing's crusaders / the first official American War picture / Taken by US Signal Corps and Navy photographers (Folder 47)
      Pershing leading troops